

# HARRISON PHILLINGHAM

STUDENT & SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

My name is Harrison and I am a 19 year old Computer Science student at the University of Essex. I am the founding president of the Computer Science and Electronic Engineering Society, and in my first year of study have achieved a First With Honours. Previously I have studied Computer Science, Psychology and Maths at Suffolk One, and for the past 3 years I have also worked part-time at my local Co-op. In my free time I enjoy furthering my programming skills by developing my Machine Learning Crypto Trading program, as well as video editing for my Church.

### **EDUCATION**

### **University of Essex**

SEP 2020 - PRESENT

Currently in the second year of a four year Integrated Masters Computer Science Course First Year Result - First With Honours, Deans List for Excellence

Second Year Results - First With Honours, Deans List for Excellence

Founder and President of Computer Science and Electronic Engineering Society

#### **Suffolk One Sixth Form College**

**SEP 2018 - JUNE 2020** 

A-level Grades (Teacher Assessed, 2020) - Computer Science (B), Psychology (B), Maths (C)

#### **Manningtree High School**

**SEP 2013 - JUNE 2018** 

GCSE Grades (2018) - Maths (8), Physics (7), Biology (7), History (7), Chemistry (6), Geography (6), English Language (6), English Literature (5), Computer Science (5), German (5) Year 8 Short Course in Citizenship (A)

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Customer Sales Assistant at East of England Co-op**

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

I currently work part-time at my local Co-op food shop, which includes customer service, stacking shelves, operating checkouts. Also supervising and tidying the warehouse, which requires me to be organised, help other staff to find where things go, and work to a deadline.

# Foundation Developer at Power Play Projects (Zero Hours Contract)

NOV 2017 - FEB 2019

This work involved creating and managing databases for the company's clients. This required me to be able to work to deadlines and think logically and systematically while understanding the client's needs.

### **Delivery Agent for Newsquest Media Group**

MAR 2016 - SEP 2019

A daily newspaper delivery round from Monday to Friday, which required me to be reliable and self-disciplined.

### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Python Development I am well versed in Python Development and this is my primary/ favoured language for development. I have passed the LinkedIn skills assessment test for Python.
- Machine Learning I am experienced in Machine Learning, including Neural Networks using libraries such as TensorFlow.
- Other languages I am also very familiar with Java, and also have some experience with C++, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I am driven to learn more about these by my want to develop my personal knowledge.
- Other professional skills I understand and have worked in an Agile Methodology style project, including using JIRA, and am also very familiar with Git.

### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS AND HOBBIES**

I am the founder and current president of the Computer Science and Electronic Engineering (CSEE) Society at my University. This was formed towards the end of lockdown in order to try and get a better connection between the students. The other executives and myself managed to take the large online group chat we used to nearly 650 members and the society to over 200 members, It it one of the largest societies on campus, and has gone on to win 'New Society of the Year 2022'. This role has enabled me to talk to a wide range of CSEE students, and also understand a lot more about many different languages and topics within the field of CSEE.

Over the past year, I have also been developing a Crypto Trading program that use Neural Networks to predict upcoming prices and buy/sell based on those predictions. I am currently in the final stages of testing before this will be released. All my knowledge on Neural Networks and TensorFlow for this has been self taught. The entire process has helped me learn a lot about software development, including initial designing and testing.

During my time at High School, I chaired 'Project 4B', an initiative with a budget of over £22,500 aimed at creating an outdoor learning area at out School. Within the 3 years that we were at school, we were able to raise the funding, create the plans and build many of the key parts. This helped further my team management and organisation skills, as I had to make sure that people carried out their roles. During my final year of High School, I held the roles of Senior Prefect and House Captain. These helped me to develop my communication skills with both students and staff, by giving presentations and leading events.

Throughout lockdown, I also edited and helped produce my church's weekly services. I did this for around 18 months, and it helped me develop proficiency in video editing using professional software. Final Cut Pro.

Outside of working, I enjoy spending time with my dog, listening to vinyls, and furthering my knowledge on cutting edge topics such as Cryptocurrencies and Artificial Intelligence.

### **CONTACT ME AT:**